<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-16T20:28:06+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">H. Plucas</title><subtitle>Inspiration &amp; Technology | I was looking for a way to collect my work, my life, my thoughts and learn new things. For this project I have created this website.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Thief of Joy!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/learning/2022/12/22/Thief-of-Joy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thief of Joy!" /><published>2022-12-22T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-22T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/learning/2022/12/22/Thief%20of%20Joy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/learning/2022/12/22/Thief-of-Joy.html">&lt;p&gt;Comparison is the Thief of Joy: How it Impacted My Decision Making and Resilience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparison is a natural tendency, but it can also be a thief of joy. When we compare ourselves to others, it can lead to negative thoughts and feelings of inadequacy. These negative thoughts can impact our decision making by causing us to doubt our own abilities, focus on the wrong things, and make decisions based on external approval rather than our own values and passions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But resilience is key to overcoming the negative impact of comparison. By building resilience, we can better handle the setbacks and challenges that come our way and bounce back stronger. This includes the negative thoughts and emotions that can arise from comparing ourselves to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cultivate resilience, it’s important to focus on gratitude, self-compassion, and personal growth. By being aware of the impact comparison can have on our decision making and actively working to combat it, we can find more joy and fulfillment in our lives and become more resilient in the face of challenges&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last friday I had the chance to participate in a resilience training with Agnes Cserhati. This inspired me to write that post.
Thanks for the great insights! #growth #gratitude #resilience&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Comparison is the Thief of Joy: How it Impacted My Decision Making and Resilience</summary></entry></feed>